Inventory of the David H. Scott Collection of Eddy Duchin Recordings, 1932-1949
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
David H. Scott collection of Eddy Duchin recordings
1932-1949
Scott, David H.
05073
6.12 cubic ft. (9 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Recordings of American dance orchestra leader Eddy Duchin collected by David H. Scott.
Biography of David H. Scott
David H. Scott began collecting recordings of Eddy Duchin’s music and radio shows in 1933. He completed the collection in 1977.
Scope and Content
The collection contains phonograph recordings of Eddy Duchin and his orchestra issued by Columbia, Brunswick, Victor, and Harmony. In addition there are radio broadcasts from 1935 to 1949, including U.S. Navy programs and the short-lived “Eddy Duchin Show.” Also included are recordings of Eddy Duchin’s solo piano performances. The collection also contains audio tapes made from the disc recordings.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by David H. Scott at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
This material was received from David H. Scott between 1973 and 1985.
Access Terms
Duchin, Eddy, 1909-1951;; Dance orchestras -- United States -- 20th century; Big Bands -- United States -- 20th century;; Phonograph records; Audiotapes
Arts, Humanities, and Social Sciences; Music
Container List
- Eddy Duchin and His Orchestra dance records (phonograph records, 10" 78 rpm), 1932-1949 (Box 1-6)
- Eddy Duchin and His Orchestra dance records, Eddy Duchin classical piano (phonograph records, 12" 78 rpm), 1932-1949 (Box 6)
- Music in the Air (phonograph record, 12" 78 rpm), undated (Box 6)
- Nathan Glantz and His Orchestra dance record (phonograph record, 10" 78 rpm), undated (Box 6)
- Boogie Woogie - Various Artists (phonograph record album, 10" 78 rpm), undated (Box 7)
- Duchin Plays Cole Porter (phonograph record album, 10" 78 rpm) (2 copies), undated (Box 7)
- Eddy Duchin (phonograph record album, 10" 78 rpm) (2 copies), undated (Box 7)
- Duchin Reminisces (phonograph record album, 10" 78 rpm), undated (Box 7)
- Eddy Duchin Plays the Music of George Gershwin (phonograph record album, 10" 78 rpm) (2 copies), undated (Box 7-8)
- Eddy Duchin Show (phonograph records, 16" 33 1/3 rpm), 1949 (Box 8)
- Eddy Duchin Piano Solos (phonograph records, 10" 78 rpm), undated (Box 8)
- Eddy Duchin Navy Programs (reel-to-reel tape, 8 mm), circa 1948-1949 (Box 8)
- Eddy Duchin and His Orchestra, Eddy Duchin Radio Programs, Eddy Duchin Piano Solos (cassette tapes, copied from phonograph records), 1932-1949 (Box 9)